Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎来到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
I'm Amira.
我是Amira。
Hey Amira, how are you today?
嘿Amira，你今天怎么样？
I'm doing great.
我很好。
What about you?
你呢？
I'm doing pretty good.
我也挺好的。
I'm excited about this lesson that you have for us today.
我对你今天给我们准备的这节课很期待。
Yes, it's actually a very, very useful lesson.
是的，这其实是一节非常非常有用的课。
It's about someone asking his boss for an assistant.
内容是有人向老板申请一个助手。
Oh, okay, an assistant.
哦，好的，助手。
What's an assistant?
什么是助手？
Well, it's someone who helps you with your work around the office.
嗯，就是在办公室里帮你处理工作的人。
Okay, great.
好的，太好了。
So let's listen to this dialogue and when we come back, we'll take a look at all the
那么我们来听这段对话，听完后我们会看看里面所有
interesting and useful vocabulary that you'll find.
有趣且有用的词汇。
Like I told you before, we just don't have the resources to hire you an assistant.
就像我之前告诉你的，我们实在没有资源给你雇一个助手。
I understand that, but the fact is we're understaffed.
我理解，但事实是我们人手不足。
The timing is just not right.
时机不对。
The economy is bad and it's too risky to take on new staff.
经济不景气，招新员工风险太大。
Yeah, I guess you're right.
是啊，我想你说得对。
Here's an idea.
我有个主意。
What if we hire an intern?
我们雇个实习生怎么样？
She would take some of the weight off my shoulders.
她可以帮我分担一些工作。
She?
她？
Yeah, you know, a recent graduate.
是啊，你知道，一个刚毕业的学生。
She could give me a hand with some of these projects and we could keep our costs down.
她可以帮我处理一些项目，我们还能控制成本。
That sounds reasonable.
听起来合理。
Let me see what I can do.
让我看看我能做些什么。
Tony, I'd like to introduce you to your new assistant.
Tony，我来给你介绍你的新助手。
Okay, great.
好的，太好了。
Let's meet her.
我们见见她吧。
Hi, I'm Adam.
嗨，我是Adam。
Oh, hi, I'm Tony.
哦，嗨，我是Tony。
And we're back.
我们回来了。
Tony, he's surprised, huh?
Tony，他很惊讶，是吧？
Yeah, he's, I don't know why though he's surprised.
是啊，他，我不知道他为什么惊讶。
I think we should talk about that a little bit later.
我觉得我们应该晚点再讨论这个。
Yes, for now, let's look at some interesting vocabulary.
是的，现在我们先来看一些有趣的词汇。
So, let's start with the first one.
那么，我们从第一个开始。
What's an assistant?
什么是助理？
Well, it's someone who helps you with your work around the office.
嗯，就是在办公室帮你处理工作的人。
I understand that, but the fact is we're understaffed.
我明白，但事实是我们人手不足。
The timing is just not right.
时机不对。
The economy is bad and it's too risky to take on new staff.
经济不景气，招聘新员工风险太大。
He could give me a hand with some of these projects and we could keep our costs down.
他可以帮我处理一些项目，这样我们就能控制成本。
That sounds reasonable.
听起来挺合理的。
But, I don't know why though he's surprised, I think we should talk about that a little
但是，我不知道他为什么惊讶，我觉得我们应该稍后再讨论这个。
bit later.
稍后。
Yes, for now, let's look at some interesting vocabulary and phrases here.
是的，现在我们先看看这里一些有趣的词汇和短语。
Marco, I know you've chosen one for us.
马可，我知道你为我们选了一个。
Yeah, the first one that I want to take a look at is resources.
是的，我想看的第一个词是资源。
Resources.
资源。
And that means in this text, basically money.
在本文中，它基本上指的是钱。
Right.
对。
So, the office doesn't have enough money.
所以，办公室没有足够的钱。
Okay, I've chosen another interesting word for you and that's money.
好的，我为你选了另一个有趣的词，那就是钱。
Money.
钱。
Okay, so, money.
好的，所以，钱。
Money.
钱。
Okay, so, money.
好的，所以，钱。
Money.
钱。
Okay, so, money.
好的，所以，钱。
Money.
钱。
Okay, so, money.
好的，所以，钱。
Now, you understand now that they're working quiteLaughs.
现在，你明白了他们工作得相当……（笑）
So, I changed my felt to the word ominous and I swapped one with my last name.
所以，我把我的感觉改成了“不祥”这个词，并且用我的姓氏替换了一个词。
Okay.
好的。
The next one here is happened a few years ago.
下一个是发生在几年前的事。
It's around this time that the city chief found someone who was stuck in the cajon and
大约在这个时候，城市负责人发现有人被困在峡谷里，
my wife started following him and making him listen to what he could tip me on, given
我妻子开始跟踪他，让他听他能给我什么提示。
that the city's safest place for coming in on his lucky day was Pサラロールカー
在他幸运的日子里，城市最安全的地方是Pサラロールカー
cite umbrella container sink, so, that's what the picture shows, the woman who's
引用雨伞容器水槽，所以，这就是图片所显示的，那位以
known for climbing mountains faster than the coffee vines.
比咖啡藤蔓还快的登山速度而闻名的女性。
working there. They don't have enough workers. Right, they don't have enough
在那里工作。他们没有足够的工人。对，他们没有足够的
employees. Perfect, okay. The next one is timing is just not right. The timing is
员工。完美，好的。下一个是时机不对。时机
just not right. The timing is just not right. The timing is just not right. Okay,
就是不对。时机就是不对。时机就是不对。好的，
let's listen to how we can use this entire phrase in a different situation
我们来听听如何在不同情境下使用这个短语，
so then we can understand what it means. Let's listen. I was gonna sell my house
这样我们就能理解它的意思。我们来听。我本来要卖掉我的房子，
but the timing is just not right. Honey, I think we should have a baby. The timing
但时机不对。亲爱的，我觉得我们应该要个孩子。时机
is just not right. Okay, great. I guess that makes it clear. Yes, actually it's
就是不对。好的，太好了。我想这已经很清楚了。是的，实际上
very obvious that it means that it's just not a good time. Right, perfect. I
很明显它的意思就是时机不合适。对，完美。我
have another interesting phrase for you which is weight off my shoulders. Weight
还有一个有趣的短语要告诉你，那就是“卸下重担”。卸下
off my shoulders. Weight off my shoulders. Weight off my shoulders. So to take
重担。卸下重担。卸下重担。所以，卸下
weight off my shoulders is another way of saying to help me with my work or to
重担是另一种说法，意思是帮我分担工作或
take some of my work away from me. If you have a lot of things to do and I come
减轻我的工作负担。如果你有很多事情要做，而我过来
and help you that means that I took some of the weight off your shoulders. Yes.
帮你，那就意味着我帮你分担了一些重担。是的。
Let's look at the next phrase that we have here and it's give me a hand. Give
我们来看下一个短语，它是“帮个忙”。帮
me a hand. Give me a hand. Give me a hand. Okay, now this is not literal. It's not
我个忙。帮我个忙。帮我个忙。好的，这不是字面意思。不是
that I'm gonna give you somebody's hand, right? Let's listen to some examples and
我要给你某人的手，对吧？我们来听一些例子，
then we can come back and explain what it means. Can you give me a hand with
然后我们再回来解释它的意思。你能帮我搬一下
these boxes?
这些箱子吗？
Neil, I'll need you to give me a hand with the sales reports. Here, let me give
尼尔，我需要你帮我处理销售报告。来，让我
you a hand with your suitcase.
帮你拿手提箱。
All right, give me a hand is another way of saying help or to help out. Exactly, to
好的，“帮个忙”是“帮助”或“帮忙”的另一种说法。没错，就是
help out. Right. Perfect. Now, the last phrase we're going to look at here in
帮忙。对。完美。现在，我们要看的最后一个短语
this dialogue is keep our costs down. Keep our costs down. Keep our costs down.
是“控制成本”。控制成本。控制成本。
Keep our costs down. So, to keep our costs down means to try and not spend so
控制成本。所以，控制成本的意思是尽量少花
much money. Exactly. Many companies, for example, now control how much printing
钱。没错。例如，许多公司现在控制你的打印量。
you do. Yes. Right. To keep the cost down of paper. Yes. So, in other words, they do
是的。对。为了降低纸张成本。是的。所以，换句话说，他们
not want to have unnecessary spending. Perfect. Okay, I think it's time for us to
不想有不必要的开支。完美。好的，我想是时候
listen to this dialogue one more time but I want everyone to listen and see
再听一遍这段对话了，但我希望大家注意听，看看
why Tony is surprised at the end when he meets his intern, when he meets his
为什么托尼在最后见到他的实习生，见到他的
assistant. Like I told you before, we just don't have the resources to hire you an
助理时会感到惊讶。就像我之前告诉你的，我们就是没有资源给你雇一个
assistant. I understand that but the fact is we're understaffed. The timing is just
助理。我理解，但事实是我们人手不足。时机就是
not right. The economy is bad and it's too risky to take on new staff. Yeah, I
不对。经济不景气，招聘新员工风险太大。是的，我
guess you're right. Here's an idea. What if we hire an intern? She would take some
猜你说得对。我有个主意。我们雇个实习生怎么样？她可以帮我
of the weight off my shoulders. She? Yeah, you know, a recent graduate. She could
分担一些重担。她？是啊，你知道，一个刚毕业的学生。她可以
give me a hand with some of these projects and we could keep our costs down.
帮我处理一些项目，而且我们可以控制成本。
That sounds reasonable. Let me see what I can do.
听起来合理。让我看看我能做些什么。
Tony, I'd like to introduce you to your new assistant. Okay, great. Let's meet her.
托尼，我来介绍一下你的新助理。好的，太好了。我们去见她吧。
Hi, I'm Adam. Oh, hi, I'm Tony. Well, you know Marco, I think that Tony was really
嗨，我是亚当。哦，嗨，我是托尼。嗯，你知道马可，我觉得托尼真的很
surprised because he was kind of hoping to have a female intern. Yeah, I think
惊讶，因为他本来希望有个女实习生。是的，我觉得
that's exactly what he was expecting. Maybe this guy is a little bit sexist. He
那正是他所期望的。也许这家伙有点性别歧视。他
thought that an intern should be a girl but instead he was... Instead he got Adam.
以为实习生应该是个女孩，但结果却是……结果他得到了亚当。
Exactly and it looks like Adam is really big and really tall because he's got
没错，而且亚当看起来又高又壮，因为他声音
that deep voice. Right. An intern, Marco, do you want to elaborate on that? Working
很深沉。对。实习生，马可，你能详细解释一下吗？在
at a company with a very low salary or sometimes no salary at all but what
一家公司工作，薪水很低，有时甚至没有薪水，但
you're gaining is experience and you are learning a lot of things. Everyone who
你获得的是经验，你学到了很多东西。每个
has been an intern or had an intern knows that sometimes they are not
当过实习生或带过实习生的人都知道，有时他们
treated all that well. Sometimes they just serve coffee or they have to do
待遇并不好。有时他们只是端咖啡，或者必须做
paperwork. Or like photocopying things. Exactly. Yeah. But some internships are
文书工作。或者像复印东西。没错。是的。但有些实习
really, really cool and some are really good experiences for learning. Yes,
真的很棒，有些是很好的学习经历。是的，
definitely. Actually, I know a friend of mine, she used to work as an intern in
当然。实际上，我知道我一个朋友，她曾经在一家
one of those really big companies and she told me that she has gained so much
大公司做实习生，她告诉我她从中获得了
experience doing that. Yeah, I mean even if you don't get paid, the experience
很多经验。是的，我的意思是，即使没有报酬，你得到的
that you get is really good and that just opens doors for maybe getting
经验真的很好，这为你打开了可能获得
another job or sometimes the interns get hired by the company to stay because
另一份工作的大门，有时实习生会被公司录用留下来，因为
they do such a good job. Yeah, I think that's mostly the case. Yeah, that
他们工作做得很好。是的，我想大多数情况都是这样。是的，这
happened to me once. I started working as an intern and after three months I was
在我身上发生过一次。我开始做实习生，三个月后我就
hired by the company so it does happen. So you did a good job. Yeah, of course.
被公司录用了，所以这确实会发生。所以你干得不错。是的，当然。
Alright folks, we're out of time today. I hope that you enjoyed our lesson and
好了，朋友们，今天的时间到了。希望你们喜欢我们的课程，
we'll be back tomorrow with another really cool and really interesting
明天我们会带来另一节来自EnglishPod的
lesson from EnglishPod. Don't forget to come to our website at EnglishPod.com
非常酷、非常有趣的课程。别忘了访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com，
where you'll find some really great and interesting resources to help you learn
那里有一些非常棒、有趣的资源，可以帮助你
and improve your English even more. Yes, you should definitely do that and Marco
更好地学习和提高英语。是的，你一定要去，而且马可
and I would love to receive your comments and suggestions that you can
和我会很高兴收到你的评论和建议，你可以
leave on our community forum. But for now it's time for us to say bye!
在我们的社区论坛上留言。但现在，我们该说再见了！